## Chunlei Peng, Ph.D. Candidate

CONTACT

VIPS Lab

INFORMATION State Key Laboratory of ISN

School of Electronic Engineering

Xidian University, No. 2 South Taibai Road

Xi'an, China, 710071

Phone: +86 15829916976

Email: clp.xidian@gmail.com

Homepage:

http://chunleipeng.com/

RESEARCH INTERESTS Machine learning, computer vision, image processing, and pattern recognition with applications to **heterogeneous image transformation** (e.g. face sketch-photo synthesis) and **heterogeneous face recognition** (e.g. matching viewed/composite/forensic sketches to face photos, and matching near-infrared/thermal-infrared images to visible light face images).

**EDUCATION** 

Sep. 2012 - Present

Ph.D. Candidate in Intelligent Information Processing

School of Electronic Engineering Xidian University, Xi'an, China

Adviser: Xinbo Gao

Sep. 2008 - July 2012

**Bachelor** in Electronic Information Engineering

School of Electronic Engineering Xidian University, Xi'an, China

Undergraduate thesis: "Adaptive Markov Random Field based Face Sketch-

Photo Synthesis" (Outstanding undergraduate thesis)

Rank: 6/543

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

- Multimedia Information Processing and Analysis, supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No. 61125204), participant, 2012.01-2015.12
- Generalized Sparse Representation based Heterogeneous Face Image Transformation and Quality Assessment, supported by National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No.61172146), participant, 2012.01-2015.12
- Heterogeneous Image Transformation and Quality Assessment, supported by the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities (Grant No. JB149901), participant, 2014.01-2015.12
- On Cross Media Heterogeneous Image Transformation and Recognition based on Big Data, Transverse Research Projects, participant, 2013.11-2015.04
- Transductive Learning based Heterogeneous Face Image Transformation from An Arbitrary Profile, supported by the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities (Grant No. K50513100009), participant, 2013.01-2013.12

#### PUBLICATIONS

#### .Journals

[1] **Chunlei Peng**, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, and Jie Li, "Graphical Representation for Heterogeneous Face Recognition," *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (IEEE TPAMI)*, Accepted, 2016.

- (Graphical representations are obtained through Markov networks, with spatial information taken into consideration. Leading performance is achieved on multiple heterogeneous face recognition scenarios.)
- [2] Chunlei Peng, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Dacheng Tao, Xuelong Li, and Jie Li, "Multiple Representations based Face Sketch-Photo Synthesis," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (IEEE TNNLS)*, Accepted, 2015. (We adaptively learn the combination weights of multiple representations, and the synthesis process is robust to different lighting conditions and backgrounds on real-world forensic sketches and mug shots.)
- [3] **Chunlei Peng**, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, "Superpixel-based Face Sketch-Photo Synthesis," *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (IEEE TCSVT)*, Accepted, 2015. (Superpixel is firstly introduced into face sketch-photo synthesis scenario, which can take inherent face structure into consideration.)
- [4] **Chunlei Peng**, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, and Jie Li, "Sparse Graphical Representation based Discriminant Analysis for Heterogeneous Face Recognition," arXiv preprint arXiv:1607.00137, 2016. (Adaptive sparse graphical representations are obtained. We further develop a spatial partition-based discriminant analysis framework including row-based, column-based, and learning-based strategies.)
- [5] Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, **Chunlei Peng**, and Chengyuan Li, "Triple Space Fusion based Face Image Recognition," *Pattern Recognition and Artificial Intelligence*, vol. 28, no. 9, pp. 811-821, 2015. (Invited, in Chinese) (Review the recent advances on heterogeneous face recognition based on triple space fusion, i.e. the fusion of the physical space, the information space, and the cognitive space.)

### Conference

- [1] **Chunlei Peng**, Nannan Wang, Xinbo Gao, and Jie Li, "Face Recognition from Multiple Stylistic Sketches: Scenarios, Datasets, and Evaluation," *European Conference on Computer Vision workshop on Visual Analysis of Sketches*, 2016. **(Oral)**
- [2] **Chunlei Peng**, Jie Li, Nannan Wang, and Xinbo Gao, "Multi-View Representation based Face Sketch Synthesis," *ACM International Conference on Internet Multimedia Computing and Service (ICIMCS)*, 2014, pp. 307-312.
- [3] Xinye Yu, Nannan Wang, **Chunlei Peng**, Jie Li, and Xinbo Gao, "Adaptive Representation-based Face Sketch Synthesis," *International Conference on Intelligence Science and Big Data Engineering (IScIDE)*, Accepted, 2016.

# **Book Chapter**

[1] Nannan Wang, Shengchuan Zhang, **Chunlei Peng**, Jie Li, and Xinbo Gao, "Face Sketch Recognition via Data-driven Synthesis," *Biometrics in Forensic Science*, Springer, 2015.

**PATENTS** 

[1] Xinbo Gao, **Chunlei Peng**, et al., "Forensic Sketch based Face Recognition," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201410166300.7, 2014.

- [2] Jie Li, **Chunlei Peng**, et al., "Multiple Features Fusion based Image Synthesis," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201410165469.0, 2014.
- [3] Xinbo Gao, **Chunlei Peng**, et al., "Graphical Representation based Face Sketch-Photo Recognition," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201510397326.7, 2015.
- [4] Xinbo Gao, **Chunlei Peng**, et al., "Superpixel based Face Sketch Synthesis," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201510395890.5, 2015.
- [5] Xinbo Gao, Wenjun Ren, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, **Chunlei Peng**, et al., "Image Quality Assessment based Synthesized Face Image Recognition," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201410133868.9, 2014.
- [6] Xinbo Gao, Yanting Hu, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, Wenjun Ren, **Chunlei Peng**, et al., "Cascade Linear Regression based Image Super-Resolution", *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201410766467.7, 2014.
- [7] Jie Li, Mingjin Zhang, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Shengchuan Zhang, **Chunlei Peng**, et al., "Support Vector Machine based Sketch Style Classification," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201410330945.X, 2014.
- [8] Xinbo Gao, Shengchuan Zhang, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, Mingjin Zhang, Yanting Hu, **Chunlei Peng**, and Wenjun Ren, "Greedy Search based Face Sketch Synthesis," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201410818175.3, 2014.
- [9] Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Wenjun Ren, Jie Li, Yanting Hu, Shengchuan Zhang, Mingjin Zhang, and **Chunlei Peng**, "Feature Similarity based Synthesized Face Sketch Quality Assessment," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201410771613.5, 2014.
- [10] Nannan Wang, Xinbo Gao, Shengchuan Zhang, Jie Li, Feng Wang, Xinye Yu, Mingjin Zhang, Chunlei Peng, and Yanting Hu, "One Target Sketch based Face Sketch Synthesis," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201510109196.2, 2015.
- [11] Nannan Wang, Xinbo Gao, Shengchuan Zhang, Jie Li, Feng Wang, Xinye Yu, Mingjin Zhang, Chunlei Peng, and Yanting Hu, "Single Photo-Sketch Pair based Face Sketch Synthesis," *Chinese Patent Pending*, No. 201510109027.9, 2015.

AWARDS	National Scholarship from Ministry of Education	2015
	Outstanding Graduate Student, Xidian University	2014
	First-Class Graduate Scholarship for PhD candidate, Xidian University	2014
	Second-Class Graduate Scholarship for PhD candidate, Xidian University	2013
	Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis, Xidian University	2012
	Third Prize in ACM-ICPC, Xidian University	2011
	Outstanding Student, Xidian University	2009

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITY

Review for **Neurocomputing** (Elsevier) from 2015;

Review for **27th IEEE International Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence (ICTAI)**, Vietri sul Mare, Italy, November, 2015.

SKILLS Proficient in Matlab, C/C++, Qt, OpenCV, Latex; Familiar with Python, Java